/ / / / HuSIC /////////////////////// 
 / / Sound driver for PC-Engine 
 / / Ver 0.26, Programmed by BouKiCHi 
 /////////////////////////////////// 

 ■ About Our Program 
 Only if you accept the terms in this document, you can use this program. 

  ■ Usage (Usage) 

 Creating · HES 
 songs mml folder to put files make_hes 
 Is generated by running the following. 
 > make_hes yoursong 
    (yoursong mml does not include the file name extension) 
   
 Creating · PCE 
 Put the file folder rommake mml make_pce the 
 Is generated by running the following. 
 > make_pce yoursong 
    (yoursong mml does not include the file name extension) 

  ■ Function (Feature) 
 · 6ch 
 , Stereo panning 
 , Sofutoueaboryumuenberopu 
 Waveform changes, 
 Mode, noise (due to hardware specification fixed 4,5 ch) 

  ■ HuSIC extended command (HuSIC exclusive command) 

 △ $ f2, switch 

 Switch = $ 00 = Noizuofu 
 Switch = $ 01 = Noizuon 

 Noise is no longer valid if the octave. (Lower 4bit enabled) 
 Also, due to hardware limitation and only 4ch and 5ch. 

   △ $ f1, wave number 

 To set the waveform from the table. 
 Wave-number means the position of the table, such as envelope data 
 Are stored in the same system. 

 △ $ f0, bread volume 

 Set the volume to another channel. 
 Top left 4 bits = ch, ch lower 4 bits = right 
 0 = lowest, 15 = best 

   △ $ ef, XPCM 

   XPCM XPCM = 1 in the mode of use 6ch 

   △ $ ee, bank number, address (lower 8bit), address (upper 8bit) 

 Change the sequence data bank exists. 

   △ $ ed, mode 
 LFO mode settings. (255 LFO stops) 
 0 = LFO No 
 A + 1 = full data modulation 
 Modulated data tracks A + 2 = * 16 (4bit shift left) 
 Modulated data tracks A + 3 = * 256 (8bit shift left) 

 Track B data modulation waveform data is used. 
 In that case, the waveform data is treated as a number of signed 5bit. 

 When enabled ※ LFO Track B will be muted. 

   △ $ ec, LFO Frequency 

 Frequency = 3.58MHz / (32 * Track B Frequency * LFO Frequency) 


  ■ When the bank switching time (attention to change bank) 

  Ripitokomando to use the bank can not exceed. 
 
  ■ History (History) 

  ver 0.01 2004/02/29- 
 Make a rush job at the end of the basic parts of Toriaezu. 
 HuC is not a place comments rather使Enairashii Kanji 
 Took some time. 

  ver 0.02 2004/03/10 
   HuC 3.20 compiler change. 
 Fixed pitch was wrong w 
 Change the way data is read. 
 Command to enable the volume. 

  ver 0.03 2004/03/11 
   6ch of. 
   Add Sofutoueaboryumuenberopukomando. 
 Add the following extended command. 
 $ F2 command (noise set) 4,5 ch in effect. 
   $ F1 command (change waveform) enabled on all channels. 

  ver 0.04 2004/03/13 
   Fixed pitch up a semitone. 
 Fixed initialization routine waveform. 

  ver 0.05 2004/03/14 
   Pitchienberopukomando, 
 Dichunkomando added. 

  ver 0.06 2004/03/15 
 How to change the volume control. 
 Pan command extensions ($ F0) added. 

  ver 0.07 2004/03/23 
   Add Ripitokomando. ($ A0, $ A1) 

  ver 0.08 2004/04/06 
 Maximum volume change to 15-31. 
 pcewave.h deleted. pce_data_table to change the name. 

  ver 0.08a 2004/04/09 
 MP added to the temporary command. 

  ver 0.08b 2004/04/10 
   To return to the wave mode at Noizukomandoofu. 

  ver 0.09 2004/04/13 
 Spread the noise frequency range (00h-1Fh up) 
 Support of the noise pitch envelope. 
 XPCM (timer-driven DirectD / A function using PCM) with 
   (First 6ch use. $ Ef = 1 on by) 
 Processing of the driver to perform VSYNC interrupt. 

  ver 0.10 2004/04/17 
 $ EE command (switch banks) added. 
 The format is $ EE, bank data, the following sequence 
 With the above modifications, was to seek the bank number to track the data pointer. 
 HES DATA when creating improvements in the structure size calculation 

  ver 0.10 (without XPCM) 2004/05/05 
   Less than a certain speed (or PCM did not respond to) test for the system. 

  ver 0.11 2004/05/27 
 LFO added functionality. 
 Reduce the frequency table 16 total. 

  ver 0.12 2004/05/28 
 Frequency tables down one octave. 

  ver 0.12a 2004/10/19 
 To the region, including a sound data when switching banks 
 Fix a bug that no longer have access. 

  ver 0.13 2004/10/23 
 Applied to different parts of 0.12a update. 

  ver 0.14 2005/01/19 
   Fixed LFO part of the trigger did not work. 

  ver 0.14a 2005/07/14 
 Each batch of ppmckc.exe to use. 
   Create a make.bat was possible to compile a particular file name independent. 
   Decided to define the internal PCE_INCLUDE batch. 
   clean.bat, make_hes_nc.bat was created. 

  ver 0.20 2005/09/08 
 PCM and timer settings, and made faster by using various jump table. 

  ver 0.21 2006/03/05 
 Update the document. Promised abolition of the section, new section of the Terms of Use. 
 hus_hes.s (main program) update 
 Add a note envelope function 

  ver 0.22 2006/03/11 
 Notes envelope modifications 

  ver 0.23 2006/03/16 
   Modify the behavior for negative values of the envelope Notes 
  
   ver 0.24 2007/04/11 
   Organize files, software re-enable the LFO 
  
   ver 0.25 2007/04/16 
   Hmckc-i insert a music file to specify the file name with. 
   Bug XPCM not play correctly. 
  
   ver 0.26 2007/04/21 
   Fixed a bug in the XPCM Kiofu. 
   Ripitokomando ($ a0) to change the specifications ppmckc. (Can be repeated in different bank) 
 
  Terms of Use ■ HuSIC Ver 1.0 (2006/03/05) 
 HuC / PCEAS for the portion of the license must follow HuC. 
 For the rest of it is available only if you agree to all the following items. 

 * Author for all phenomena that occur as a result of using this program, 
 Distributor and will not bear any responsibility. Available only in individual responsibility. 
 , Used, modified, built only in accordance with all other terms used, can be done free of charge and free. 
 If you leave the state to redistribute, and modify the source files contained in this archive, 
 To specify the information about a change, please included in the archive. 
 • The distribution of the source state, must be included in this document, including the Terms of Use. 
 • The binary distribution of the state is free to use only in accordance with all other terms 
 File, or you can configure the archive. 
